<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tsiao Wang&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tsiao Wang&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wangtsiao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polynomial and Number Theoretic Transform</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/lagrange-poly-ntt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/lagrange-poly-ntt/</guid>
      <description>Polynomials are an fundamental mathematical tool within the field of cryptography, where they play a vital role in the design of zero knowledge proofs and the implementation of secure communication systems. In cryptography, the utilization of polynomials diverges from their traditional usage, as they are defined over a finite field rather than the real numbers. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, all operations discussed in this blog pertain to integers within a finite field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding Scheme: A Remarkable Breakthrough in ZKP</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/folding-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/folding-schemes/</guid>
      <description>A folding scheme is defined with respect to an NP relation, and it is a protocol between an untrusted prover and a verifier. Both entities hold two N-sized NP instances, and the prover in addition holds purported witnesses for both instances. The protocol enables the prover and the verifier to output a single N-sized NP instance, which we refer to as a folded instance. A folding scheme guarantees that the folded instance is satisfiable only if the original instances are satisfiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groth16 Zero Knowledege Proof Made Not Simple</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/groth16-snark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/groth16-snark/</guid>
      <description>1. Preliminaries 1.1 Bilinear Groups The proof system works with bilinear groups $(p, \mathbb{G}_1, \mathbb{G}_2, \mathbb{G}_T, e)$ with the following properties:
$\mathbb{G}_1, \mathbb{G}_2, \mathbb{G}_T$ are groups of prime order p $e: \mathbb{G}_1 \times \mathbb{G}_2 \rightarrow \mathbb{G}_T$ is a bilinear map i.e., $e(U^a, V^b)=e(U, V)^{ab}$ If $G$ is a generator for $\mathbb{G}_1$ and $H$ is a generator for $\mathbb{G}_2$ then $e(G, H)$ is a generator for $\mathbb{G}_T$. There are efficient algorithms for computing group operations, evaluating the bilinear map, deciding membership of the groups, deciding equality of group elements and sampling generators of the groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Zero-knowledge Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/zeroknowledge-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/zeroknowledge-vm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note on IPA/DARKS/KZG Polynomial Commitment</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/polynomial-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/polynomial-commitment/</guid>
      <description>Polynomial commitment is a cryptographic tool that has numerous applications in areas such as blockchain, zero-knowledge proofs, and secure multiparty computation. It allows one party to commit and later prove to another party that the committed data satisfies certain properties.
In this post, I will present several polynomial commitment schemes that have proven to be highly valuable, including IPA, DARKS, and KZG. Furthermore, I will provide a comparison of these schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying convex optimazation to arbitrage in CFMM</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/convex-arbitrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/convex-arbitrage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where will MEV in blockchain go?</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/mev-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/posts/mev-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>// TODO: Preface
Content
MEV and several seacher&amp;rsquo;s strategies Original, PBS, and MEV-boost Transaction order-fair consensus algorithm What other opportunities exist in 2023? Reference:
Eden: https://cosmic-bublanina-39bfbc.netlify.app/
Flashbot: https://www.flashbots.net/
Bloxroute: https://bloxroute.com/
Skip protocol: https://skip.money/
Order-fair: https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3494105.3526239</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I am Tisao Wang, welcome to my website where I share my thoughts and some technological posts. Currently I am doing MSc at the Peking University and sometimes I do some research at the blockchain research center.
Now I am an intern zero knowledge researcher at a famous DAO lab which dedicated to bring the cutting-edge cryptography technology to the decentralized world. Our vision is scaling Ethereum, onboarding the next millions users to web3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://wangtsiao.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangtsiao.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
